

MOHAMMED R. S. SUNOQROT

@ mohammed.sunogrot@ntnu.no ntnu.edu/employees/mohammed.sunogrot

J +47 466 325 87

✓ Overlege Bratts veg 4B, Trondheim, 7026 Norway in mohammed-r-s-sunogrot

MohammedSunogrot

0000-0001-9239-1683

Norwegian/Palestinian | Born: 1991

ABOUT

I am a researcher with a PhD in medical technology and a background in Biomedical engineering. I have significant experience in developing & managing AI systems, data analysis & management, image analysis. innovation management, commercialization mapping, and navigating regulations for AI-based medical software.

EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Researcher

Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

July 2022 - Present

■ Trondheim, Norway

- Led and managed the full cycle of an AI product (PROVIZ).
- Elevated TRL, obtained fund (around 4M NOK), & worked on commercializing an innovative AI system (PROVIZ).
- Successfully conducted & designed a proof-of-technology, prospective clinical study for AI diagnosis system (NCT06000046).
- Fully prepared & wrote regulatory documents for software as medical device and obtained approval (REK KULMU A; identifier: 479272).
- Developed AI systems for prostate cancer detection.
- Supervised master students.
- Collaborated on international projects to improve AI diagnosis systems.
- Participated in the REACH incubator program (Read) and the Forge accelerator program (Read).

Innovation Project Manager

Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

a Jan 2022 - July 2022

- Trondheim, Norway
- Investigated innovation for AI solutions of prostate cancer diagnosis.
- Increased technology readiness levels for an AI for radiology product.
- Landscaped the market & initiated meetings with industry & customers.
- Coordinated with technology transfer office, & industry partners.

Researcher

Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

- Trondheim, Norway
- Developed machine & deep learning methods for MRI image analysis.
- Analyzed, processed, & managed medical images.
- Taught & supervised master students.

Data & Cloud Manager & Coordinator [Part-time] Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

May 2018 - Present

- Trondheim, Norway
- Managed & organized a number of HUNT cloud labs for CIMORe Group.
- Coordinated labs (compliance, data, privacy, technical, & knowledge).
- Monitored & troubleshooted the labs activities.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Medical Technology **NTNU**

Mar 2017 - Aug 2021
Trondheim, Norway

Thesis title: Computer-Aided Diagnosis of Prostate Cancer Using Multiparametric MRI.

Thesis

M.Sc. in Biomedical Engineering **University of Dundee**

Graduated with a Distinction.

Thesis title: Microultrasound scanning of Oesophogeal tissue.

Thesis

B.Sc. in Biomedical Engineering **German-Jordanian University**

Thesis title: Radiation Doses And Risks From Computed Tomography In Jordan.

Thesis

B.Sc. in Biomedical Engineering **Koblenz University of Applied Sciences**

Exchange year.

SKILLS

Al Data Science Innovation Healthcare Regulations Project Management Data Analysis & Management Medical Imaging Presentation Supervising Scientific Writing **Proposals Preparing & Writing** Machine Learning Deep Learning Python

GitHub

Linux

Cloud

PATENT

Matlab



Patent Co-inventor

Docker

Machine & deep learning solutions for radiology. International Application No. PCT/EP2023/061976 (Pending).

- Collected, managed, organized, & secured MR image cohorts.
- Maintained data privacy & security.
- Monitored image quality & data integrity.

Doctoral Researcher

Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

- Mar 2017 Aug 2021
- Trondheim, Norway
- Developed machine & deep learning models for MR image analysis.
- Designed, run, & analyzed experiments on AI for prostate cancer diagnosis.
- Participated & presented in national & international projects & conferences.

Lecturer

Korea-Palestine Centre & Palestine Polytechnic University

- **Aug** 2016 Dec 2016
- Hebron, Palestine
- Taught a course on MATLAB programming & image processing.

Intern

Koblenz University of Applied Sciences (Hochschule Koblenz)

- **Mar 2013 Jul 2013**
- Remagen, Germany
- Investigated optical tracking system at the Medical Robotics Laboratory.
- Designed, run, & analyzed experiments related to robotic laser osteotomy.

Intern

Al-Ahli Hospital, Department of Biomedical Engineering

- **Aug** 2011 Sep 2011
- Hebron, Palestine
- Maintained a variety of medical diagnostic & therapeutic equipment.
- Performed repairs & adjustments to medical equipment.

PROJECTS

Prostate Cancer Visualization by MRI (PROVIZ) Research Council of Norway/NTNU

- **2019** Present
- Trondheim, Norway
- Lead the project to apply for a patent.
- Helped joining & coordinating with the Olso cancer cluster pre-incubator.
- Obtained fund (500 K NOK) from Norwegian Cancer Society.
- Obtained fund (1.5 M NOK) from Digital Life Norway. Read
- Co-obtained fund (1 M NOK) from NTNU Discovery main. Read
- Co-obtained fund (500 K NOK) from Research Council of Norway.
- Secured fund (200 K NOK) & coordinated with external collaborators. Read
- Manged & lead the innovation programme (Fund = 600 K NOK). Read
- Managed the Product, Data, & Cloud.

Al-based decision support system for detection and localization of prostate cancer

Liaison Committee between the Central Norway RHA and NTNU/NTNU REFEREES

- **2022 Present**
- Trondheim, Norway
- I am the project leader/Principal Investigator.
- I received 4 million NOK fund.
- Prepared a project proposal & budget.
- Working on developing & improving AI tools.
- Working on testing AI solutions in the clinic.

LANGUAGES

| English | •••• |
|-----------|------|
| Arabic | •••• |
| Norwegian | •••• |
| German | •••• |

SCIENTIFIC

More than 12 Journal publications, 25 Conference posters/abstracts, 1 Book chapter, and 6 invited Academic lectures. Supervisor for 3 Master students and 2 Bachelor students. Cristin: 891930 D 0000-0001-9239-1683

BOARD MEMBERSHIPS

Board member

Det Muslimske Samfunnet i Trondheim

- Helped run a 3,500+ member volunteer organization with 83+ nationalities.
- Organized & run social & educational activities.
- Applied for funding & attended meetings with government, NGOs & dialogue centers.
- Led meetings on events, feedback, and finances.

Board Treasurer & Deputy leader **NTNUI** Karate

- 苗 Nov 2019 Aug 2021 🖣 Trondheim, Norway
- Managed all financial aspects of the NTNUI Karate group, ensuring financial stability & transparency.

MEMBERSHIPS

- International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine (ISMRM).
- Digital Life Norway (DLN).
- Norwegian Society of Graduate Technical and Scientific Professionals (Tekna).
- Jordan Engineers Association.
- Palestine Engineers Association.

Available upon request.